The Shinigami Mercenaries have five members, not four.
死神僱傭兵團的成員有五個 不是四個
Then where is--
那另一個…
Don't tell me…
該不會是…
What are you doing? Quick, let's go to Boss.
你在幹嘛？我們快去找團長吧
We're back up to four mercenaries, and the boss is a powerful illusionist.
至少有四名僱傭兵 而且團長是強大的幻術師
If I don't return to my body before he joins them…
如果不在團長和他們匯合之前 換回身體的話…
Let's catch them ourselves. The fox and the mountain gods.
我們自己去抓吧，那隻狐狸和山神們
What? But why?
什麼？為什麼？
They killed Ushiuchibo and got me too.
他們殺了牛打坊，還刺傷了我
And we only have one treasure.
而我們只拿到一件寶物
What would Boss say to that?
團長會怎麼說？
It's scary when Boss gets mad.
團長生氣的樣子很可怕
Gather around.
圍過來
From now on, you guys…
從現在起，你們記住…
Wait. Where's the guardian stone?
等等，守護石在哪裡？
EPISODE 11
（第 11 集）
You said they attacked you. You lost it to them?
你說你遇襲了 守護石被他們搶走了嗎？
That's what I should be asking. What did you do to my guardian stone, huh?
我還想問呢 你們把我的守護石怎麼了？
What? I mean, the one who got it stolen is the fool, no?
幹嘛？弄丟的人自己才是笨蛋吧？
It was you, huh?
是妳對不對？
-Give it. -Give what?
-交出來 -交什麼？
Give me my treasure.
把我的寶物還給我
You said let's catch the mercenaries first!
你明明講過我們先抓僱傭兵的！
-Where did you hide it? Hand it over! -Gosh, it's mine!
-藏在哪裡？交出來！ -天哪，這是我的！
-No, it's mine! -Give it!
-不行，是我的！ -交出來！
Where do you think you're touching?
你亂摸什麼？
Why are they fighting each other?
他們為什麼打起來了？
What does it matter? Nyudo will take care of the fox.
這有什麼關係？入道會對付那隻狐狸
You take the girl and I'll take him over there.
你對付那個女人，那邊的男人交給我
I told you, it's mine.
我說過了，它是我的
They're here.
他們來了
What's this now?
現在是怎樣？
-Your opponent is me. -Bring it.
-你的對手是我 -放馬過來吧
We have another fine young man. But Yuki is no child!
又找到一位帥哥 但宥淇可不是小孩子！
I already know of your talents, Yuki-onna.
雪女，我已經知道妳的法術了
I want that body too.
我也想要那具身體
You shit!
混帳！
Darn it!
該死！
Why you--
你竟敢…
Why, why?
幹嘛？
-You idiot! I'm Nyudo! -Nyudo is with us!
-笨蛋，我是入道啊！ -入道和我們在一起！
-That guy is the nine-tailed fox! -You liar. I'm not stupid!
-那個人是九尾狐！ -撒謊，我又不是傻子！
Gosh, you freakin' idiot.
天哪，你這個白痴
Yeon, strike him!
阿硯，砍他！
No!
不要！
Ice.
冰
Yeon.
阿硯
Why would you--
你為什麼…
I'm not Lee Yeon. I'm Nyudo of the Shinigami Mercenaries.
我不是李硯 我是死神僱傭兵團的入道
Thanks. You all can go now.
謝謝，妳們可以走了
Here you go.
藥來了
How come she's not waking up?
她為什麼還不醒來？
Lord Lee Rang, you drink it too.
李朗大人，你也喝藥吧
You've been hurt badly!
你傷得很重！
-I don't need it. -Please just drink. Damn it!
-我不需要 -求求你快喝藥吧，真是的！
You must live for Mrs. Boss to live.
為了頭目夫人，你也要活下去啊
Koo Shin-ju and I risked our lives to save you.
我和具申炷都冒著生命危險去救你
So, damn it! Just drink it!
該死的！快喝藥！
My goodness.
天哪
Please.
求求妳
Please wake up.
求求妳醒來吧
So this one is on our side?
原來這個人是我們這邊的啊？
-Must I repeat myself, darn it? -What? So Nyudo was actually the fox?
-可惡，非要我再講一遍嗎？ -什麼？入道變成那隻狐狸了？
Yes, I'm Nyudo.
沒錯，我是入道
Hong-joo, Moo-yeong. Please hang in there a little longer.
紅酒、無影，請你們再堅持一下
It's three against one. Just give up.
現在是三對一，放棄抵抗吧
She's quite strong.
她的力氣很大的
Bring it!
來吧！
Ice.
冰
I got you.
凍住妳了
I hate you.
我討厭妳
I'll especially freeze up the insides of your lungs too.
所以我要把妳的肺也凍住
I found it!
找到了！
How dare you hurt Yuki!
你竟敢傷害宥淇！
That prick. How did he unfreeze my ice?
那個混蛋，他怎麼可能融化我的冰？
-Have your skills gone stale? -There's no way.
-妳的法力失效了？ -不可能
No, don't!
不要！
It's gonna take some time. My body is pretty battered from the poison.
這需要一些時間 我已經被毒藥折磨得精疲力盡了
Damn.
該死
So that guy controls fire? Gosh, I want that skill too.
原來他會控制火？ 天哪，我也想要這種法術
That's why my skills didn't work. Nyudo! Switch bodies with him!
難怪我的法術不起作用 入道，和他交換身體！
Darn it.
真是的
Before I do, let's destroy this body first!
在那之前，先毀掉這具身體吧！
Damn, it's such a waste.
天哪，好浪費喔
Damn it!
該死！
Hurry. Hurry and melt!
快點，快點融化！
No, no!
不要啊！
Now's the time!
時機到了！
Darn, prick. How dare you!
可惡，你這個混蛋竟敢搗亂！
I'm back in my own body.
我找回自己的身體了
Oogama, I'll try again. Hold him tight!
大蝦蟆，我再試一次 你牢牢地按住他！
Please move!
拜託動起來啊！
Yeon!
阿硯！
Oh, no. Nyudo-- Nyudo is--
不，入道他…他…
Let go!
放手！
-Moo-yeong. -I'm fine.
-無影 -我沒事
-Are you awake? -I'm not dead, right?
-妳醒了？ -我沒死掉吧？
It was close, but you're still alive.
差一點，但妳還活著
Did you get hurt because of me?
你是因為我受傷的嗎？
-You're a mess. -I'm fine.
-到處都是血 -我沒事
You're awake, so nothing else matters.
妳醒了，其他的都不重要了
I was so scared
我好怕
that I'd never get to see you again.
好怕再也見不到你
I promised to follow you to the afterlife.
我保證過要追隨妳去來世的
I love you.
我愛你
What?
什麼？
I love you, Rang.
我愛你，阿朗
Goodness.
天哪
Gosh, the three of us are a complete mess.
哎呀，我們三個太狼狽了吧
But still, we won.
但我們還是贏了
We're back at the hotel.
我們回到飯店了
It truly was one hell of a night.
真是地獄般的一夜啊
Gosh. Let's go to Myoyeongak and treat our wounds first.
天哪，我們先去妙緣閣療傷吧
Hold on. I need to check on Rang first.
等一下，我先去看看阿朗
Oh, my-- My goodness.
哎呀，真是的
All the Yachas are gone.
所有的夜叉都不見了
Gosh, that punk. I knew he'd take care of it.
天哪，那個臭小子 我就知道他應付得來
What's for lunch today?
今天中午吃什麼？
-Madame, there's a reservation call. -We're not taking guests this week.
-閣長，有人打電話來預約 -我們本週不接待顧客
-Say your boss was stabbed. -It's a group reservation, ma'am.
-就說閣長被刺傷了 -是團體預約啊，閣長
A group reservation? How many?
團體？多少人？
A group? I should take them in then.
團體？那我應該接待一下
Is that prick Cheon Moo-yeong here?
千無影那個混蛋在嗎？
Oh, my. He had his reasons.
哎呀，他有他的苦衷
Reasons, my foot. We almost died because of him.
什麼狗屁苦衷，我們差點被他害死
I'll take care of it.
我會找他算帳的
Don't let him go alive.
別讓他活著離開
-I won't let it slide. -Okay.
-我不會善罷甘休的 -知道了
-Gosh, who the hell is it? -Who?
-天哪，到底是誰呢？ -你在說什麼？
The one who killed all the Yachas at once.
一下子殺光所有夜叉的人
There was another one of them. It was probably him.
僱傭兵團裡還有一個人，也許是他
The Shinigami Mercenaries' boss.
死神僱傭兵團的團長
-Hey, you're bleeding! -Oh, gosh. I hope it's not infected.
-喂，你流血了！ -天哪，希望沒有感染才好
-Rang. -Yeah?
-阿朗 -嗯？
Why don't you have a shadow?
你為什麼沒有影子？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
The sunlight is this bright, yet…
陽光這麼強烈，可是…
Guys!
兩位！
You scared me. Why?
你嚇我一跳，怎麼了？
Do you guys happen to remember how we got back to Myoyeongak?
你們還記得 我們是怎麼回到妙緣閣的嗎？
-What are you suddenly on about? -Tell me!
-你沒頭沒腦的在說什麼？ -告訴我！
After fighting all night, we got back to Room 404, and…
奮戰一夜後 我們回到404號房，然後…
-Huh? How did we get here? -Why don't we remember anything?
-啊？我們是怎麼來到這裡的？ -為什麼大家一點印象都沒有？
Wait. Be quiet.
等一下，安靜一點
-Can you hear that? -This music.
-你們聽見了嗎？ -這首曲子
Wh-- What's that doing in my room?
它怎麼會在我的房間裡？
-This isn't Myoyeongak. -What?
-這裡不是妙緣閣 -什麼？
We are…
我們…
still in Room 404.
還在404號房
Oh, shit.
該死
-Gosh. -Who are you?
-天哪 -你是誰？
The Hypnotism Society.
催眠術協會
Please, let's talk instead! I'm the only son in the family line.
拜託，有話好好講！我是家裡的獨苗
I'm the boss of the Shinigami Mercenaries.
我是死神僱傭兵團的團長
The name is Satori.
悟
From now on, you can't take one step out of this room.
從現在起，不准你們走出房間一步
Until you die.
直到死為止
-You can try. -Oh, before that…
-放馬過來啊 -在那之前
give me your treasures.
把你的寶物交出來
You crazy prick, you make me laugh.
瘋子，你也太可笑了吧
One, two, three.
一、二、三
-Yeon! -Have you lost your mind?
-阿硯！ -你瘋了嗎？
Don't be surprised.
別驚訝啊
Because this one was charmed from the very beginning.
這傢伙從一開始就被幻術蠱惑了
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Gosh, what's the rush?
哎呀，急什麼？
-Yeon. -What the--
-阿硯 -怎麼…
-What did I just do? -I woke you to show you something special.
-我剛剛做了什麼？ -我喚醒你是想請你看好戲
You see, I wish you'd strangle each other.
希望你們能掐死對方
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Moo-yeong, don't do it!
無影，別這樣！
Hong-joo!
紅酒！
No, don't! Let go!
不要，別這樣！放手！
It's no use, because I charmed them too.
沒用的 因為他們也被我的幻術蠱惑了
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Guys, please!
拜託你們清醒一下！
How do you feel now?
感覺如何？
How disappointing.
真讓人失望
You killed two of us with these skills?
你們就憑這點本事 殺了我們僱傭兵團的兩名成員？
That's enough.
夠了
Now that I've given you the treasures, please just stop.
既然寶物都給你了，就請你罷休吧
How great. The mountain god of Joseon is pleading.
太棒了吧，朝鮮山神求饒了
But that's too bad.
只可惜
Not a single being has ever left my battlefield alive.
從來沒有誰能活著離開我的戰場
-Please stop. -Are you surrendering?
-求求你停下來 -你在投降嗎？
No.
不是
Hooray.
萬歲
What are you trying to say?
你胡說什麼？
I said, "Hooray."
我說“萬歲”
Hooray.
萬歲
You crazy fool-- What's this? What are you doing?
你這個瘋子…幹嘛？你要做什麼？
Ice.
冰
What the hell are you--
妳到底在做…
You may not know it, but a nine-tailed fox has similar skills.
你可能不知道 九尾狐也會類似的幻術
From now on, you guys…
從現在起，你們記住…
When I say "hooray" thrice, the guy before me is the enemy.
只要我說三遍“萬歲” 我面前的人就是敵人
Don't ask, don't argue. Just finish him off.
不要問，不要爭論，直接殺死他
-Moo-yeong. -Hong-joo.
-無影 -紅酒
Don't ever slight a mountain god of Joseon again, kid.
再也別輕視朝鮮山神了，小子
Throw him off the roof.
把他從屋頂上丟下去
Oh, geez.
天哪
You okay?
沒事吧？
-Hey, you guys just jump off with him. -Yes, sir.
-對了，你們也跟他一起跳下去 -是
What? Cheon Moo-yeong!
什麼？千無影！
Hey!
站住！
Damn it.
該死
D-2 DAYS
（倒數計時，兩天）
People died at the Bando Hotel?
坂東飯店死人了？
-What bastard would dare that at my hotel? -What about Ginko's wedding?
-哪個混蛋敢在我的飯店殺人？ -銀子的婚禮怎麼辦？
Honey, how can we hold a wedding where people died?
老公，我們怎麼可以 在死過人的地方舉辦婚禮呢？
-Goodness. -Oh, dear.
-哎 -真是的
I'm fine with that.
我不介意
All the more reason to show that the Bando Hotel is thriving.
我們更應該讓他們看到 坂東飯店依然生機勃勃
That we, the Tawaras, are unshakable.
看到我們俵家不可撼動
Well said!
講得好！
We just need to stop the reporters and get rid of the bodies!
我們只要攔住記者 把屍體清理出去就好了！
You're more like my daughter now.
妳現在更像是我的好女兒了
My wedding will be attended by the Governor-General's key figures,
總督府的關鍵人物 和朝鮮最臭名昭彰的親日組織
and Joseon's most notorious pro-Japanese groups.
都會出席我的婚禮
Don't tell me you're targeting your wedding?
妳該不會要對自己的婚禮下手吧？
I'll gather them all in one place, and boom!
我會把他們聚集在一處，然後…轟！
We blow them up.
炸死他們
I hear you tailor the best suits in all of Gyeongseong.
聽說妳是京城最好的西裝裁縫
We're closed.
我們打烊了
Don't you know who I am?
妳不知道我是誰嗎？
My bride is a regular here, Ginko Tawara.
我的新娘經常光顧妳的店 她叫俵銀子
I've heard a lot about you, sir.
久仰您的大名
Our wedding is this Sunday, so I'm here to get a suit fitted.
我們本週日舉行婚禮 所以我來訂做西裝
It's an honor, sir.
我深感榮幸
Isn't Ginko such a charming woman?
銀子是個迷人的女人吧？
What do you like about her?
您喜歡她哪一點？
Her flame withstands all tramples, just like any other Joseon girl.
就像所有朝鮮女孩子一樣 她的氣焰經得起各種踐踏
As the one doing the trampling, it's extremely exhilarating, you know.
身為踐踏者 我覺得這種特質讓人興奮
That's why I like Joseon.
這正是我喜歡朝鮮的原因
Smile a little.
笑一個
I said, smile.
我叫妳笑
Fourth Branch of Gyeongseong's Independence Volunteer Corps, no?
京城獨立志願軍第四支部，是吧？
Most of the war chest funds going to Manchuria moves through you.
流向滿洲的大部分戰爭資金 都是透過妳轉移的
Why are you so surprised?
為什麼一臉驚訝？
As of today, the first three branches don't exist.
如今，前三個支部已經不存在了
All its members were shot dead.
所有成員都被槍斃了
But…
但是…
why do you think this place still stands?
妳覺得為什麼這間店還能開下去？
-If you want to kill me, just do it. -Well.
-想殺我就動手吧 -嗯
That's no fun, is it?
那就不好玩了
Tell this to my bride.
轉告我的新娘
Don't even think of having hope.
別想著抱有任何希望
And that I know everything.
我什麼都知道
I'm counting on you for my suit, Water Snail Bride.
我的西裝就靠妳了，田螺姑娘
-Geez! That movie sucked, huh? -Yeah.
-天哪！這部電影爛透了，對不對？ -是啊
Still, it's been ages since we did this. Has it been 300 years?
不過我們已經很久沒看過電影了 有三百年了吧？
-Honey. -Yeah?
-老公 -嗯？
Can you get me some bingsu or whatever?
你幫我買一份刨冰什麼的好不好？
-Bingsu? -Yeah.
-刨冰？ -嗯
Okay, I'll be right back.
好，我去去就回
I must go to my brother.
我必須去找哥哥
Moo-yeong! Hey, Moo-yeong!
無影！嘿，無影！
Wake up, Moo-yeong!
醒醒啊，無影！
I gather you're the one who had Cheon Moo-yeong's back, sir?
幫助千無影的人是你吧，第十王？
Well, I wouldn't say I had his back.
算不上幫助
No political statements please. All I did was pure business.
不要講政治，我純粹是做生意
-Business, indeed. -Shut up, sir!
-做生意 -閉嘴啦！
Shut-- Shame on you. You shut that mouth of yours!
閉嘴…不知廉恥，妳才該閉嘴！
Seniority exists, even in the afterlife.
即便在來世，也要講究資歷的
Well. I guess I'll just go tell the King of the Dead.
好吧，我直接去告訴閻羅王
Don't tell on me!
不要告狀！
My intentions were pure, okay?
我的意圖很純粹的，好嗎？
-Pure? -The world is in shambles these days.
-純粹？ -如今世界一片混亂
It teems with the innocent dead, no?
無辜的死者遍地都是
It's already in shambles. Is it so bad to turn it upside down?
既然已經一塌糊塗了 鬧它個天翻地覆又如何？
Turn the world upside down?
鬧它個天翻地覆？
What is the reason Moo-yeong came to this era?
無影來到這個時代有什麼目的？
Don't you have an idea?
妳不知道嗎？
He is dead. I saw it with my own eyes.
他死了，我親眼所見
Who is he?
他是誰？
I raised him as my own. Please take good care of him.
我把他當親生兒子養大的 拜託妳好好照顧他
He's injured all over.
他渾身都是傷
I'm not sure if he's going to make it.
不知道能不能撐過去
Even so, he's a descendant of the Siberian tigers.
不管怎麼說，他都是東北虎的後代
I'm sure he'll wake up.
我相信他會醒過來的
What did the Chief Commissioner say?
首席專員說了什麼？
He came to warn you.
他是來警告妳的
-That he knows everything. -And the bombs?
-他說他什麼都知道 -炸彈呢？
I didn't get caught, but I'm anxious. Wouldn't it be better to change our plans?
沒有被他發現，但我心裡很不安 我們應該改變計劃才對吧？
No, this is our only chance. We must push ahead.
不行，這是我們唯一的機會 必須繼續推進
The organization has fallen. You can't do it alone.
組織已經崩塌了 妳一個人是做不到的
Isn't there one left?
不是還有一位成員嗎？
The perfect reinforcement for the job.
這項任務的完美後援
Your life sure is dynamic.
你的生活真是多采多姿
You're here for less than a month, and you survived death how many times?
來到這裡不到一個月 看看你已經有幾次差點沒命了
Excuse me.
打擾了
You're getting married? Do you even know what he is?
妳要結婚？妳知道他是什麼東西嗎？
I know that he's not human.
我知道他不是人類
-If you know, then why? -I'll set off a bomb at my wedding.
-既然知道，為什麼還要結婚？ -我要在婚禮上引爆炸彈
-Then what about you? -I was ready since I entered the corps.
-那妳怎麼辦？ -我從加入組織的第一天就準備好了
Why do all women who look like this go big or go home?
為什麼長著這張臉的女人 都喜歡玩大的？
Let's say you sacrifice your life.
即便妳犧牲自己的生命
-But will it kill a demon of that caliber? -That's why I need you, Koo Shin-ju.
-真的能殺死那麼厲害的妖怪嗎？ -所以我需要你幫忙，具申炷
-When is the wedding? -This Sunday at 6:00 p.m.
-婚禮什麼時候舉行？ -本週日下午六點
Who the hell gets married at night?
哪有人在晚上結婚的？
The Governor will attend after his Gyeonggi inspection tour.
總督巡視完京畿後就會來參加婚禮
Wait, if it's Sunday…
等等，如果是週日…
It's in two days. The day of the lunar eclipse.
那就是兩天後，月食之日
A lunar eclipse?
月食？
I'm sorry, Eun-ho, but I can't go on that day.
對不起，恩好，我那天去不了
I'll go.
我去吧
-Lord Lee Yeon! -I don't know about anything else,
-李硯大人！ -別的我不知道
but we're a nation that never fails to attend celebratory events, no?
但我們這個民族 從不缺席慶祝活動的，對不對？
I heard you were against Shin-ju being an independence activist. So why?
我聽說你曾經反對申炷 成為獨立運動分子，為什麼要幫我？
Because I have some debt to settle with your soon-to-be husband.
因為我要找妳的未婚夫算帳
That wedding.
那場婚禮
I'll make it the funeral of the century.
會被我變成世紀葬禮
The Shinigami Mercenaries lost to the nine-tailed fox?
死神僱傭兵團輸給了那隻九尾狐？
-And the treasures? -They've lost them.
-寶物呢？ -被他們弄丟了
I send five of the greatest talents,
我派出五員大將
but I get neither the fox's neck nor the treasures?
結果既沒拿到狐狸的首級 也沒拿到寶物？
-I wonder why that is. -The mercenaries were being sloppy.
-怎麼會呢 -是僱傭兵團草率了
That damn mentality is why we got played by that fox!
正是這種心態 害我們被那隻狐狸耍得團團轉！
-He's a master of schemes. -No, this has nothing to do with that.
-他是詭計大師 -不是這個原因
The moment he sent Madame Ryu here to lure the mercenaries to the hotel,
他派柳閣長前來 引僱傭兵團進入飯店時
he was painting a picture.
就已經謀劃好了
One that would rattle the tables.
藉機讓我們自亂陣腳
You're overestimating the enemy, sir.
您高估敵人了
When you're at war, the one who respects the opponent wins.
作戰的時候，尊重對手的人才能獲勝
If I were the nine-tailed fox,
假如我是那隻九尾狐
how would I counterattack?
我會怎麼反擊呢？
Now we rattle them from our side too.
現在我們也要擾亂他們
Hey! My foot's asleep.
喂，我的腳麻了
Be a bit patient!
耐心一點！
I thought we were ambushing a wedding.
我們不是要伏擊一場婚禮嗎？
Why make dumplings? Are we fighting with them?
為什麼要包餃子？ 想拿餃子當武器嗎？
I won't be here after two days.
再過兩天我就不在這裡了
That's what I'm saying. Why waste your time on this?
就是說嘛 為什麼要在這種事情上浪費時間？
Your body's still a mess too.
你的身體還沒好呢
Hey, it looks like I'll be fighting until the moment I leave.
看樣子，我要戰鬥到 臨走前的最後一刻了
Can't I just make some dumplings with my only brother for today?
今天就不能 和唯一的弟弟一起包餃子嗎？
Gosh, what kind of person says their good-byes with dumplings?
真是的，哪有人用餃子道別的？
It'll only make us sad, if it's too extravagant a farewell.
太隆重的告別徒增傷心
Even if I'm not here,
我走之後
just think I went on a trip after making some dumplings.
你就當我包完餃子去旅行了吧
I'll live just fine without you.
沒有你，我也可以活得很好
Now that I've spent a month with you, I'm already sick of you.
這個月和你生活在一起 我已經受夠你了
Always creating trouble, getting hurt, and tricking me.
一直惹是生非、受傷、耍弄我
Gosh, I don't like you either. You're a picky eater and you talk back.
天哪，我也不喜歡你 你老是愛挑食，還頂嘴
Not once have I ever seen you come home by your curfew, geez.
我還沒看到你哪一次 是在宵禁之前回家的，真是的
You're an awfully restless sleeper.
你睡相很差
-Picky eater! -Opium addict!
-你挑食！ -你吸鴉片！
Yes, that's how you do it.
沒錯，這樣才對
If you miss me by any chance,
如果你想我了
just remember the ugly things, like now.
就像現在這樣想想我的缺點吧
I'll do that too.
我也會那麼做
Let's make a promise. To never cry.
我們做個約定吧，永遠不要哭
Send me off with a smile until the end.
帶著笑容送我離開
I promise.
我答應你
-Hurry up. -No, I don't want to!
-快點 -我不要！
-You must wash it to heal faster. -But it--
-洗一洗才好得快 -可是…
-Hey, just sit! -But it's going to sting!
-坐下！ -可是會刺痛！
-You're the one to talk! -Take off-- That's cold!
-你還知道痛！ -脫掉…水好冷！
-Hey, hey! -You do it then!
-喂！ -那你去洗啊！
He's over a thousand years old but he's playing so heartily.
他一千多歲了，還玩得這麼開心
This is the first time I've seen Boss smile like that.
我第一次見到老大笑成這樣
Will they never see each other after tomorrow?
明天過後 他們就永遠見不到彼此了嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
Never.
永遠
-I don't want to! -Hey, damn it! Hey!
-我不要洗！ -該死！
That's still on your arm?
那東西還在你手臂上嗎？
Oh, this? You're right.
這個嗎？是啊
But because of your pure nature, you will lose your way.
但是你本性純潔，會迷失自己的路
She hopes this will help you find your way.
她希望這個印記能幫你找到你的路
Since the fortune god gifted me this, I guess it must be something good.
既然是財神送我的，一定是好東西吧
Give me my present you call a cell phone. You said you'd give it after a month.
把那個叫手機的禮物給我吧 你答應過一個月後會送給我的
Damn, you haven't forgotten.
該死，你還沒忘記
Here. You can have it, but you can't use it here anyway.
拿去，我可以把它給你 但是你在這裡用不了
-No battery, no cell tower. -You scammed me again?
-沒有電池，也沒有基地台 -你又騙我？
So I've prepared something else.
所以我為你準備了其他禮物
Ta-da!
看！
-A golden ax? -What do you think? So cool, huh?
-金斧頭？ -怎麼樣？很酷吧？
If you pull them out during fights you'll look super rich and trendy!
打架的時候掏出來 看起來超級有錢又時髦！
-You idiot, you know how weak gold is? -It's gold-plated.
-笨蛋，你知道黃金有多軟嗎？ -是鍍金的
Geez. My goodness.
天哪
Up until a month ago, I thought to kill you if I ever met you.
一個月前，我還想在見到你時殺死你
Well, the world tends to stab you in the back like that.
這世界喜歡在背後捅刀
A diner will suddenly change its name once you're done saving its coupons.
可能你剛集滿一家餐廳的優惠券 它就換了新名字
Stock information from a friend will always tank.
朋友介紹的股票永遠會跌
What are you on about?
你在講什麼？
The world may stab you in the back.
世界可能會背棄你
But by having the right person by you, either a lover or a family member,
但是只要身邊有對的人 無論是愛人還是家人
you will never fall.
你就永遠不會失足
I'm saying, live a good life.
我是叫你好好生活
Even if I'm not here, live briskly. With your Little Mermaid.
即便我不在，你也要精神抖擻地 和你的小人魚一起生活
Whatever. I'm going to sleep.
隨便啦，我要睡覺了
You're okay.
沒事了
You'll get better, ma'am.
閣長，妳會好起來的
-When did you wake up? -Just now.
-妳什麼時候醒來的？ -剛醒
How can you be smiling? You were on the brink of death, Madame!
居然還在笑？ 妳可是差點死掉耶，閣長！
But it all just feels fruitless.
感覺一切都徒勞無功
-I lost the treasure. -Does that even matter right now?
-我弄丟了寶物 -現在還管什麼寶物？
Why put yourself in harm's way?
妳為什麼要以身犯險？
I won't die so easily. How could I die with you holding on to me?
我沒那麼容易死掉的 有你這樣拉著我，我怎麼會死呢？
Promise me that you won't get hurt again.
答應我，再也不要受傷了
Let me get hurt instead, since I'm okay with dying!
讓我替妳受傷吧，反正我不怕死！
Why would you die, brat?
臭小子，為什麼要你去死？
You're mine.
你是我的
Don't cry.
不要哭
After Yeon leaves, let's take the girls to the hot springs.
阿硯離開後 我們帶女孩們去泡溫泉吧
Apricot.
梅花姊
They have something to say to you.
她們有話想跟妳說
You go first.
妳先講
No, you first.
不要，妳先講
About trying to kill that girl at the hotel, and pushing you and stuff.
我們想在飯店殺死那個女生 還推妳什麼的
-Sorry about that. -And thanks for not telling Mr. Lee Rang.
-對不起 -還有，謝謝妳沒告訴李朗大人
They said they did it because they were so scared.
她們說她們是因為害怕才那麼做的
Life isn't so easy, huh?
生活很不容易吧？
Seeing all that, working for a non-human Madame.
要目睹那一切 在非人類的閣長手下效力
But the last thing I want is for you to have blood on your hands.
但我最不想看到的就是妳們手上沾血
It's the first time that's hard. After that, it gets easier.
第一次很難，但後面會愈來愈輕鬆
My brother said so.
是我哥哥告訴我的
Apricot.
梅花姊
Is that Madame's medicine? Here, we'll do it.
這是閣長的藥嗎？交給我們吧
Thank you for everything, ma'am.
店長，感謝您的照料
You seem full of stories but I won't pry.
你好像有很多故事，但我不想多問
Instead, can you sell something for me?
不如幫我賣掉一些東西吧？
This boutique…
這家洋品店…
will be closing soon.
很快就要倒閉了
It seems to be doing well, so why?
看起來生意不錯，怎麼會倒閉呢？
These are such times, no?
因為時代艱難啊
By any chance, do you make deliveries too?
店長，你們有送貨的服務嗎？
What pretty shoes.
好漂亮的鞋子
-Who's it from? -I was told not to reveal the name.
-誰送的？ -那個人不讓我透露姓名
But they left a message.
但是有留言給妳
"These shoes are expensive and pretty,
“這雙鞋昂貴又漂亮
but they look like they'll hurt your toes."
但是看起來會磨腳”
The paths I took all my life were all headed towards you.
我一生選擇的道路都是走向妳
I tried…
我試過…
running away, in case my misfortune rubbed off on you.
逃跑，不希望我的不幸拖累妳
But I couldn't get too far.
但我總是走不遠
So, Hong-joo.
所以，紅酒
Wear these shoes, and by the time you get a callus…
穿上這雙鞋，等妳磨出繭的時候…
think of me a little too.
也想想我吧
It's a perfect fit.
正好合腳
He didn't say where he was going?
他沒說他要去哪嗎？
No, Madame.
沒有
It's fine.
沒關係
He won't be able to get too far from me anyway.
反正他沒辦法離我太遠
Delicious as always.
還是那麼好吃
Ta-da.
看
Pretty, huh? Moo-yeong bought them for me.
好看吧？無影買給我的
Looks like the watermelons from Mt. Mudeung.
看起來像無等山的西瓜
Wanna fight?
想打架嗎？
I'm leaving tomorrow.
我明天就要走了
What if you miss the lunar eclipse? You can never go, right?
如果你錯過月食呢？ 永遠都回不去了對不對？
Should I just smash the moon into two?
要不要我把月亮劈成兩半？
I'll go, even if the sky falls. I must.
就算天塌下來我也要走，必須走
You're looking calmer than I imagined. After losing the ruler to Moo-yeong.
你被無影搶走了金尺 居然還能這麼冷靜
Right. You can still go home as long as you have the stone.
也對，只要有守護石，你還是能回家
Before I go, I'll get the Governor's head.
離開之前，我要拿到總督的首級
The Chief Commissioner?
首席專員呢？
Let's do it together.
我們聯手吧
I'm the only one who belongs in this era.
只有我屬於這個時代
You were high on opium, and Moo-yeong was turned to stone.
你只顧著吸鴉片 無影又被變成了石柱
You think I haven't fought back?
你以為我沒反抗過嗎？
I'm sure you did. Alone, with all your might.
我相信妳一定有 全力以赴地孤軍奮戰
No matter how hard I tried,
無論我多麼努力
they hunted anything, whether animal or human.
他們還是獵殺了所有的生命 無論是動物還是人
Their blood forming rivers in all of Joseon.
朝鮮各地血流成河
But nothing changed.
什麼都沒有改變
Hong-joo, I know the future. And what happens to Joseon.
紅酒，我知道未來 也知道朝鮮會發生什麼事
I'm dying to know, but don't spoil it.
我很好奇，但是不要告訴我
I hate foul play.
我討厭犯規
Well, it's not like what I do will make a big difference to the future.
雖然我的行為對未來影響甚微
But still, I'll do what I can in my place right now.
但我還是要盡我所能，出一份力
As the last mountain god of Joseon.
作為朝鮮最後的山神
I'd love be swayed to join you.
我也想和你聯手
But you are bound to leave, while I'm the one who'll be left behind.
但你註定要離開，而我會被留下來
Leave me out of it.
我不插手了
D-1 DAY
（倒數計時，一天）
-You okay? Let me see. -Gosh, seriously. What are they doing now?
-好了嗎？讓我看看 -真是的，他們在幹嘛？
Oh, my. Who is this handsome guy?
天哪，這位帥哥是誰？
Remember that a man is defined by his hair, fashion, and eyebrows.
記住，男人靠的是髮型、時裝和眉毛
You're such a stylish man since you're from the future, huh?
你是從未來來的 所以超級時髦，對不對？
But who will trim my brows once you leave?
可是等你走後，誰幫我修眉毛呢？
I promise to look for you in that era, Mi-yeon.
我保證一定會好好照顧那個時代的你 米緣
After all, we're friends.
畢竟我們是朋友嘛
Geez.
天哪
-Gosh, I'm gonna-- -Hey, Mr. Jindo!
-天哪，我要… -珍島先生！
-Where are you going? -To get some seolleongtang for Madame.
-你要去哪裡？ -去幫閣長買先農湯
Have some sikhye first.
先喝點食醯吧
Thank you.
謝謝
You like Madame Ryu, huh?
你喜歡柳閣長吧？
Am I wrong?
我說錯了嗎？
No wonder. I heard him wailing in her room this morning.
難怪，今天早上 我聽見他在她房間裡嚎啕大哭
Well, that's not-- You heard wrong!
不是的…你聽錯了！
I clearly heard it with my own ears too.
我也聽見了，很清楚
Gosh, that's not what happened!
天哪，不是那樣的！
Ho-yeong.
哥哥
And the treasures?
寶物呢？
That's the first thing you ask? How disappointing.
你只關心這個嗎？真讓人失望
Were you hurt badly?
你傷得很重嗎？
It's no big deal.
沒什麼大不了
But I could only get this one.
但我只拿到這一件寶物
When my body's fully recovered, I'll get the guardian stone from Lee Yeon.
等我的傷徹底痊癒 我會從李硯手中搶到守護石的
-When is Lee Yeon leaving? -Tomorrow.
-李硯什麼時候走？ -明天
We don't have time. Let's do it now.
我們沒時間了，現在就開始吧
Right now?
現在？
With just the golden ruler? What if it fails?
只用金尺嗎？萬一失敗怎麼辦？
It's not your fault, but only my fate.
我不會怪你，只能怪我命不好
Ho-yeong, answer me one question.
哥哥，回答我一個問題
What will you do first, when you're revived?
你復活之後要做的第一件事是什麼？
What about you? What did you come all the way here for?
你呢？ 你不辭辛苦地來到這裡是為了什麼？
My dream…
我的夢想…
is to…
就是…
live a normal life with you.
和你一起過上普通的生活
In a normal house, driving a normal car.
住普通的房子，開普通的車
Wondering what to eat for lunch tomorrow with you.
和你一起思考明天中午要吃什麼
We'll go to the bathhouse on weekends.
週末一起去澡堂泡澡
Seriously.
真的
Like a very, very normal…
像其他家庭一樣…
Like any other family.
過非常普通的生活
So, Ho-yeong.
所以，哥哥
Please come back to me.
請你回到我身邊吧
So you lost the golden ruler?
你把金尺弄丟了？
Just tell me honestly. What is all this?
跟我說實話，這到底是怎麼回事？
I'm thinking nothing was ever a coincidence.
我認為這一切都不是巧合
My coming to this era to retrieve this stone,
我來到這個時代尋找守護石
and the ruler falling into my hands.
而金尺也恰恰落入我手中
What's this? He doesn't have a face.
這是什麼？這個人沒有臉
In the beginning, there was only one mountain god, not four.
最初，山神只有一位，而不是四位
The original mountain god?
原始山神？
But I heard he lost it, so demons began to be born on this land.
但我聽說他發瘋了 所以這片土地上開始生出妖怪
The King of the Dead killed him.
於是閻羅王殺了他
After which, the king divided the original's power into four gems.
然後，閻羅王 把原始山神的法力化為四件寶物
Sealing them all in different eras. The stone and the ruler being one of them.
封存在四個不同的時代 守護石和金尺就是其中兩件
That's why the guardian stone was in the future, where I came from,
難怪守護石在我生活的未來
and why the golden ruler was here.
金尺卻在這裡
Those two should not exist in the same era.
這兩件寶物不該存在於同一時代
Because they attract each other like magnets.
因為它們會像磁鐵一樣互相吸引
To become one, like it originally was.
努力變回原來的一體
I'll take the stone back to the future. So what's the worry?
我就要把守護石帶回未來了 有什麼好擔心的？
The ruler Moo-yeong took.
無影奪走了金尺
He's trying to awaken something with the golden ruler.
他想用金尺喚醒某樣東西
I know, it's his older brother.
我知道，是他哥哥
It's…
難道…
not his brother?
不是他哥哥？
If it's not him, then…
如果不是他哥哥，那麼…
It can't be!
不可能！
No, Moo-yeong!
不可以，無影！
He can't wake that up!
他不能喚醒那個東西！
Then we must stop him.
那我們必須阻止他
Why just observe?
為什麼坐視不理呢？
Because he's just an empty vessel now.
因為他現在只是一具空殼
The only way to catch him is to wake him up.
只有喚醒他，才能抓住他
Why make things so dangerous, huh?
為什麼要用這麼冒險的辦法？
Because it's my duty to protect this era.
因為我的職責是守護這個時代
Then what about Moo-yeong? Who will protect him?
那無影呢？誰來守護他？
You seem to forget at times.
妳時不時會忘記
But old hag, we're not your pawns. We feel pain when we get hurt.
我們不是妳的棋子，老妖婆 我們受傷的時候也會痛
We feel hurt when a parental figure like you abandons us.
我們被母親一樣的妳拋棄時也會傷心
That child you turned to stone!
那個被妳變成石柱的孩子！
He wants to live. Even if he has to beg for time, he wants to live!
他想活下去 哪怕是苦苦哀求，他也想要活下去！
It's a gift.
送你的
Paper cranes?
紙鶴嗎？
I folded all one hundred of them thinking of you.
這一百隻紙鶴是我想著你折出來的
Then your love comes true, they say.
據說這樣會如願得到愛情
Forever.
永遠的愛情
I always seem to be receiving.
好像接受禮物的人一直是我
From you.
不管是妳的禮物
And from Lee Yeon.
還是李硯的禮物
-One seolleongtang to go, please. -Me too.
-一份先農湯，外帶 -我也要
Give us a bowl each, okay? He'll pay.
給我們一人一碗吧，他請客
-It's been a while, sir. -Indeed.
-好久不見了，老闆 -是啊
Did you guys follow me here? But why should I pay?
你們是不是跟蹤我？ 為什麼要我請客？
I have no money. I got fired from my part-time job here.
我沒錢，我在這家店打工時被開除了
I don't either. Boss banned robbery, arson, and even pickpocketing.
我也沒錢 老大禁止我們搶劫、放火，甚至扒竊
Oh, gosh.
天哪
Jae-yoo, have a bowl too.
載宇，你也喝一碗吧
No, I have to get it to Madame Ryu. She has to eat it warm.
不了，我要給柳閣長送湯 她必須趁熱喝
Geez, that damn Jindo. He only thinks about his owner.
天哪，這隻可惡的珍島犬 他的心裡只有主人
A virtuous man indeed!
果然是品德端正的好男人！
No, no, no.
不…
You promised to come back.
你答應過要回來的
You promised, but why?
你答應過的，為什麼？
Why did you leave me behind?
為什麼拋下我？
I don't have anyone now.
我現在誰都沒有了
I only have you, Ho-yeong.
只有你，哥哥
No, no, no, no.
不，不要啊
No!
不要！
No, no, no.
不…
Moo-yeong.
無影
Ho-yeong.
哥哥
You did it, brother.
你成功了，哥哥
Ho-yeong, you did it.
哥哥，你成功了
We did it, Ho-yeong.
我們成功了，哥哥
Ho-yeong.
哥哥
You did it.
你做到了
Thank you for coming back.
謝謝你回來
Thank you for coming back alive, Ho-yeong.
謝謝你活著回來，哥哥
Don't die, Moo-yeong!
不要死啊，無影！
Not yet, no!
現在還不行！
Gosh, Ho-yeong. I can't breathe.
哥哥，我不能呼吸了
-I'm not your brother. -Huh?
-我不是你哥哥 -啊？
Thanks for your hard work, mountain god of the north.
辛苦你了，北邊山神
Your role ends here.
你的使命完成了
Oh, goodness.
天哪
Can't muster your strength, can you? It's because your heart stopped.
使不出力氣吧？因為你的心臟不跳了
What the hell have I awakened?
我到底喚醒了什麼東西？
People called me "the original mountain god."
大家都叫我“原始山神”
It is because of me that your brother went batshit crazy.
你哥哥是因為我才發瘋的
It was me who told you how to save your brother too.
也是我告訴你怎麼救你哥哥的
I had to find my scattered powers.
我必須找回我散落的法力
Everything's turning dark, no? It's the light of death.
眼前愈來愈黑了吧？那是死亡之光
And it suits you better.
它更適合你
Is this the end for me?
這就是我的結局嗎？
In this deserted place…
在這個荒無人煙的地方…
with not one person to grieve for me…
沒有一個人為我傷悲…
Dying here alone.
孤獨地死去
Is that my ending?
這就是我的結局？
I'm screwed.
完蛋了
Where did it all go wrong?
是在哪裡出了錯？
What kind of person do you know me as?
妳眼中的我是什麼樣子？
You wanted to be a doctor instead of a mountain god.
你想成為醫生而不是山神
You cherished every single blade of grass.
你珍惜每一片草
You got back up when you got hurt.
你受傷之後總能重新站起來
But you cried your eyes out when Yeon or I got hurt.
但是我或阿硯受傷時，你會哭成淚人
We were young then.
那是我們小時候
And I've changed.
如今的我已經變了
Ta-da.
看
But still, Hong-joo.
但是，紅酒
There are things in the world that don't change.
這世上有些東西不會變
I miss you.
我好想妳
If it means I'd see you one last time…
如果活著就能見妳最後一面…
I want to live too.
那我也想活下去
Moo-yeong! Cheon Moo-yeong!
無影！千無影！
Hey, can you hear me?
聽得見嗎？
Wake up! Come on, Moo-yeong.
醒醒！快醒醒，無影
Wake up, Cheon Moo-yeong.
醒醒啊，千無影
You have to fight me.
你還要和我打架
You didn't get revenge on me yet.
你還沒找我報仇呢
I wonder why Yeon looks like he's about to cry?
阿硯為什麼一副要哭出來的樣子？
Moo-yeong.
無影
You're not going to die. You can't die yet.
你不會死的，還不能死
So stop playing weak and get up, you bastard!
不要再裝虛弱了，快起來，混蛋！
You're giving me this, so what?
你現在要給我這個？
I have…
我…
wronged you so much.
一直錯怪你了
Don't apologize. I won't accept it.
不要道歉，我不接受
You think I'll forgive you if you go like this?
你以為你這樣離開 我就會原諒你嗎？
Don't be ridiculous!
別傻了！
Please protect Hong-joo.
拜託你好好保護紅酒
Wake up.
醒醒
Hey, wake up.
醒醒吧
Don't die.
不要死
Please don't die, Moo-yeong.
求求你不要死，無影
Don't die!
不要死！
-Perhaps… -Moo-yeong.
-也許… -無影
…they were always there.
…他們一直都在
My family.
我的家人
My real brother.
我真正的兄弟
Selling Park's powder! Pretty norigaes too!
賣朴氏粉唷！還有漂亮的絲絛！
-Hold this real quick. -Where are you going?
-妳先拿一下 -你要去哪裡？
I'll be right back.
我馬上回來
This one and…
這個，還有…
Well, a man's going some place far. Which one's the sturdiest?
要送給要去遠方的人 哪一個最結實？
Rang.
阿朗
Rang!
阿朗！
Who are you?
妳是誰？
Hello, tasty and nutritious mermaid lady.
妳好，美味營養的人魚小姐
Moo-yeong!
無影！
No.
不
Jae-yoo!
載宇！
Jae-yoo?
載宇？
The blood amount tells me it wasn't fatal.
從出血量看，不是致命傷
-She was taken alive. -Who did this?
-她是被活捉的 -是誰幹的？
The mercenaries are still alive.
僱傭兵團還活著
-Rang. -It's all my fault.
-阿朗 -都是我的錯
I shouldn't have left her alone. I left her there.
我不該丟下她一個人 我把她丟在街上了
-Let go. You'll get hurt. -Aren't I pathetic?
-放手，你會受傷的 -我是不是很沒用？
I can't even protect anyone.
誰都保護不好
I'm neither human nor a fox, but just a half-breed.
我既不是人類，也不是狐狸 只是個血統不正的東西
Why was I born like this?
為什麼我生來就是這樣？
-Rang, that's enough. -Just go.
-阿朗，夠了 -你走吧
-You leave in a few hours anyway. -How could I leave you like this?
-反正你幾小時後就會離開 -我怎麼能這樣丟下你不管？
Don't worry and just go…
別擔心，你走吧…
to your home where the human is waiting.
那個人類還在家等你呢
I was never one of your options from the start.
反正我從來都不在你的選擇之中
You know how many sword-cuts I have right now?
你知道我身上有多少傷口嗎？
I got cut so much, it doesn't even hurt now!
多到已經感覺不到痛了！
But--
可是…
Even a splinter in your finger breaks my heart.
你手指上的一根小刺都會讓我心碎
When I think about leaving you, I feel like I might lose my mind.
一想到要離開你，我就痛不欲生
Yeo-hee's not here.
汝熙不在了
But if you leave too, I'm…
如果你也離開，我…
I promise I won't leave you alone.
我保證不會留下你一個人
I promise.
我保證
Don't go.
不要走
Please have my back, so I can fight.
請你支持我，讓我全力戰鬥
D-DAY 11:00 A.M.
（離開當天，上午十一點）
If you don't find the treasure today, the hostages will die.
如果你不能在今天找到寶物 人質就會死
He's starting a battle of wits.
他要開始和我們鬥智了
Our weakness is time.
我們的弱點是時間
We must save them, and catch the shits within the time limit.
我們必須在有限的時間裡 救出他們並抓住那些混帳
You're a weak one, huh?
你很弱是吧？
Jae-yoo. Jae-yoo!
載宇，載宇！
Will you alone be able to change Joseon?
你能靠一己之力改變朝鮮嗎？
I'm sort of setting an example. That I will fight to the end.
我是在樹立榜樣，我要戰鬥到底
Believe in yourself, just like I believe in you.
相信自己，就像我相信你一樣
You are not the owners of this land.
你們不是這片土地的主人
TRANSLATED BY TIFFANY NAYEON HWANG
字幕翻譯：鄒琳